<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="book_titles">
        <item>The Bell Jar by Sylvia Plath (1961)</item>
        <item>Gone with the Wind by Margaret Mitchell (1936)</item>
        <item>The Scarlet Letter by Nathaniel Hawthorne (1850)</item>
        <item>1984 by George Orwell </item>
        <item>The Catcher in the Rye by J.D Salinger (1951)</item>
        <item>Animal Farm by George Orwell (1949)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="summaries">
        <item>A sombre coming of age story where the protagonist, Esther, deals with a series of life-changing experiences
            most would approach with pleasure and excitement, but as Esther moves forward on her journey she descends deeper into madness.
            This book provides an in-depth look at mental health and the conventional expectations
            placed on women at the time. Just don’t take this book to the beach with you.</item>
        <item>One of my absolute favourite books of all time – it’s not a light read and the sheer size
            of it (1000+ page) may put even the most devout literary buffs off, but once you get into
             the world of Scarlett O’Hara you’ll fall in love with the South and all its trimmings.
             A historical novel that has you rooting for a rich spoilt heroine whose bound and determined to survive.
             Read this book when you need that extra bump of determination and may there be a little Scarlett O’Hara in all of us.
        </item>
        <item>Hawthorne can be a bit tedious at times but who doesn’t like a sultry book
            about sin and lust? He was writing about the Puritan society of 1642 so don’t think you’re in for a
            sequel to 50 Shades of Grey. Once you figure out the language of the time you’ll uncover that poor Hester
            Prynne must wear a scarlet ‘A’ on her chest at all times to signal to the world that she is an adulteress
            – imagine that in today’s London!
        </item>
        <item>Written 35 years before its dated title, 1984 is a dystopian prediction of what the future holds,
            which is a lot of tyranny, censorship, mind control, public surveillance (Big Brother) and war. Orwell
            explores what used to be England and is now an authoritarian state. Translated into more than 65 languages,
            this is an important work of science fiction. A book that helps us examine what our fundamental freedoms
            are and will question just about everything you thought you knew.
        </item>

        <item>Holden Caulfield is a 16-year-old undergoing treatment in a mental facility. The story
            takes place in New York where Holden spends three days prior to returning to his parents home
            for Christmas, after he’s recently been expelled from school. What follows is a diatribe of meetings,
            calls and random occurrences when he seems to be obsessed with where the birds from central park go when
            the water freezes. The story explores alienation and loneliness as well as the struggle of growing up.
        </item>
        <item>Animal Farm by George Orwell (1949): George Orwell was a crafty fellow. I read this for
            the first time when I was in high school and I had no idea it went any deeper than a bunch of
            animals bound together to take over a farm from a farmer. Of course, it soon became clear that this
            is an important piece of historical literature. It’s a critique of the Russian Revolution and symbolizes
            better than anything else I’ve ever read, the rule of a dictator (Joseph Stalin in this instance) in their country.
            Set aside your personal political views to get a better understanding of the ideologies this book presents on freedom and equality.
        </item>
    </string-array>


</resources>

